# Jun Xing (邢骏)

Lead researcher, miHoYo (米哈游)

http://junxnui.github.io/

junxnui@gmail.com

# RESEARCH

My research combines modern concepts in computer graphics, computer vision, deep learning and human computer interaction, with broad applications in 2D/3D /animation/audio contents authoring, analysis, and synthesis. In particular, I am interested in high-quality digital human modeling and rigging, performance capturing and retargeting, cloth and hair simulation, etc.. My goal is to design interactive/predictive systems and deep learning-based algorithms to free the artists from the tedious works so they can focus on creation.

# **EDUCATION**

University of Hong Kong	2012.09 — 2016.12
PhD in computer science, advised by Dr. Li-Yi Wei	
University of Science and Technology of China (USTC)	2008.09 - 2012.06
Bachelor in Electronic Engineering and Information	

WORK EXPERIENCE	
Joint Laboratory between Ruijin Hospital (瑞金医院) and miHoYo (米哈游) Deputy director, Shanghai	2021.03—ongoing
miHoYo (米哈游) Lead researcher, Shanghai	2019.01—ongoing
USC Institute for Creative Technologies  Postdoctoral researcher, supervised by Hao Li, Vision and Graphics Lab, Los Ange	2017.05 — 2019.01 cles
Adobe Research Graphics research intern, Procedural Imaging Group, San Jose	2016.07—2016.09
Autodesk Research HCI Graphics research intern, UI Graphics Group, Toronto	2016.01 — 2016.04
Microsoft Research Asia Graphics research intern, Visual Computing Group, Beijing	2014.12-2015.04

# **PUBLICATIONS**

# [18] Revisiting Knowledge Distillation: An Inheritance and Exploration Framework

Zhen Huang, Xu Shen, Jun Xing, Tongliang Liu, Xinmei Tian, Houqiang Li, Bing Deng, Jianqiang Huang, Xiansheng Hua

#### [17] Intuitive, Interactive Beard and Hair Synthesis with Generative Models

Kyle Olszewski, Duygu Ceylan, *Jun Xing*, Jose I. Echevarria, Zhili Chen, Weikai Chen, Hao Li *CVPR 2020 (Oral)* 

#### [16] Learning Formation of Physically-based Face Attributes

Ruilong Li, Kalle Bladin, Yajie Zhao, Chinmay Chinara, Owen Ingraham, Pengda Xiang, Xinglei Ren, Pratusha Prasad, Biping Kishore, *Jun Xing*, Hao Li

CVPR 2020

# [15] Deep Face Normalization

Koki Nagano, Jaewoo Seo, Huiwen Luo, Zejian Wang, *Jun Xing*, Liwen Hu, Lingyu Wei, Hao Li *SIGGRAPH Asia 2019* 

#### [14] Learning Perspective Undistortion of Portraits

Yajie Zhao, Zeng Huang, Tianye Li, Weikai Chen, Chloe LeGendre, Xinglei Ren, *Jun Xing*, Ari Shapiro, Hao Li *ICCV 2019 (Oral)* 

#### [13] HairBrush for Immersive Data-Driven Hair Modeling

Jun Xing, Koki Nagano, Weikai Chen, Haotian Xu, Li-Yi Wei, Yajie Zhao, Jingwan Lu, Byungmoon Kim, Hao Li UIST 2019

#### [12] Quantization Network

Jiwei Yang, Xu Shen, *Jun Xing*, Xinmei Tian, Houqiang Li, Bing Deng, Jianqiang Huang, Xiansheng Hua *CVPR 2019* 

#### [11] Mask-off: Synthesizing Face Images in the Presence of Head-mounted Displays

Yajie Zhao, Qingguo Xu, Weikai Chen, *Jun Xing*, Chao Du, Xinyu Huang, Ruigang Yang *IEEE VR 2019* 

#### [10] paGAN: Real-time Avatars Using Dynamic Textures

Koki Nagano, Jaewoo Seo, *Jun Xing*, Lingyu Wei, Zimo Li, Shunsuke Saito, Aviral Agarwal, Jens Fursund, Hao Li *SIGGRAPH Asia 2018* 

# [9] HairNet: Single-View Hair Reconstruction using Convolutional Neural Networks

Yi Zhou, Liwen Hu, *Jun Xing*, Weikai Chen, Han-Wei Kung, Xin Tong, Hao Li *ECCV 2018* 

#### [8] Deep Volumetric Video from Very Sparse Multi-View Performance Capture

Zeng Huang, Tianye Li, Weikai Chen, Yajie Zhao, *Jun Xing*, Chloe LeGendre, Linjie Luo, Chongyang Ma, Hao Li *ECCV 2018* 

# [7] Identity Preserving Face Completion for Large Ocular Region Occlusion

Yajie Zhao, Weikai Chen, *Jun Xing*, Xiaoming Li, Zach Bessinger, Fuchang Liu, Wangmeng Zuo, Ruigang Yang *BMVC 2018* 

#### [6] Autocomplete 3D Sculpting

Mengqi Peng, *Jun Xing*, Li-Yi Wei *SIGGRAPH 2018* 

# [5] Mesoscopic Facial Geometry Inference using Deep Neural Networks

Loc Huynh, Weikai Chen, Shunsuke Saito, *Jun Xing*, Koki Nagano, Andrew Jones, Hao Li, Paul Debevec *CVPR 2018 (Spotlight)* 

#### [4] Sequence-to-Sequence Learning via Shared Latent Representation

Xu Shen, Xinmei Tian, *Jun Xing*, Yong Rui, Dacheng Tao *AAAI 2018* 

# [3] Energy-Brushes: Interactive Tools for Illustrating Stylized Elemental Dynamics

Jun Xing, Rubaiat Habib Kazi, Tovi Grossman, Li-Yi Wei, Jos Stam, George Fitzmaurice UIST 2016

# [2] Autocomplete Hand-drawn Animations

Jun Xing, Li-Yi Wei, Takaaki Shiratori, and Koji Yatani SIGGRAPH Asia 2015

#### [1] Autocomplete Painting Repetitions

Jun Xing, Hsiang-Ting Chen and Li-Yi Wei SIGGRAPH Asia 2014

# **EXHIBITIONS**

#### VR Hair Salon for Avatars

Jun Xing, Liwen Hu, Koki Nagano, Li-Yi Wei, Hao Li. SIGGRAPH 2019 Real-time Live!

# Pinscreen Avatars in your Pocket: Mobile paGAN engine and Personalized Gaming

Koki Nagano, Shunsuke Saito, Mclean Goldwhite, Kyle San, Aaron Hong, Liwen Hu, Lingyu Wei, *Jun Xing*, Qingguo Xu, Hanwei Kung, Jiale Kuang, Aviral Agarwal, Erik Castellanos, Jaewoo Seo, Jens Fursund, Hao Li. *SIGGRAPH Asia 2018 Real-time Live!* 

#### Deep Learning-Based Photoreal Avatars for Online Virtual Worlds in iOS

Koki Nagano, Jaewoo Seo, *Jun Xing*, Kyle San, Aaron Hong, Mclean Goldwhite, Jiale Kuang, Aviral Agarwal, Caleb Arthur, Hanwei Kung, Stuti Rastogi, Carrie Sun, Stephen Chen, Jens Fursund, Hao Li. *SIGGRAPH 2018 Real-time Live!* 

#### MEDIA & PRESS

# HairBrush for Immersive Data-Driven Hair Modeling

Befores&Afters;

paGAN: Real-time Avatars Using Dynamic Textures

SIGGRAPH Asia 2018 Technica Papers Trailer; fxGuide; LA Times;

CBS News; CBC News; Netflix Original and Buzzfeed; Channel One News;

Cartoon Brew; NTV (Nippon TV) News;

# HairNet: Single-View Hair Reconstruction using Convolutional Neural Networks

Nvidia News; MIT Tech Review;

#### **Autocomplete 3D Sculpting**

3Dnchu; MIT Tech Review;

# **Autocomplete Hand-drawn Animations**

WIRED; FastCompany; The Next Web; AnimationWeek; MentalFloss;

CoolThings; TechTimes; 3Dnchu; CGPress;

#### TECHNICAL REPORTS & PATENTS

# **Techniques for Generating Dynamic Effects Animations**

Jun Xing, Rubaiat Habib Kazi, Tovi Grossman, Li-Yi Wei, Jos Stam, George Fitzmaurice US Patent 10467794 granted November 5, 2019

# Deep RBFNet: Point Cloud Feature Learning using Radial Basis Functions

Weikai Chen, Xiaoguang Han, Guanbin Li, Chao Chen, *Jun Xing*, Yajie Zhao, Hao Li arXiv:1812.04302.

# **ACADEMIC SERVICE**

#### **Committee Member:**

IJCAI 2020

AAAI 2019, 2020

International Conference on Computational Visual Media (CVM) 2019

Pacific Graphics 2018

SIGGRAPH Emerging Technology 2017

#### Reviewer:

Computer Vision: CVPR; ECCV; ICCV; ACCV; TIP;

Computer Graphics: SIGGRAPH /SIGGRAPH Asia; PG; VRST;

Human Computer Interaction: CHI; UIST;

# PROFESSIONAL SKILLS

Designer: neural network, algorithm, UI/UX, system

Programmer: C/C++, Python/Pytorch, Qt, Java, OpenGL/CV/VR, Unity

# REFERENCES

Prof. Hao LiPinscreen, USC, ICT, hao@hao-li.comDr. Rubaiat Habib KaziAdobe Research, rhabib@adobe.com

Prof. Tovi Grossman University of Toronto, tovi@dgp.toronto.edu

Dr. Jos Stam Nvidia, stam.jos@gmail.com